<?xml version="1.0"?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>AI News</title><link>https://ainews.ukiuni.com/</link><description>AI related news</description><item><title><![CDATA[I took apart a 9,000,000mAh power bank from eBay to learn the truth - here's what's inside]]></title><link>https://www.zdnet.com/article/i-tested-a-9000000mah-battery-pack-from-ebay-that-cost-10-heres-my-verdict/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 02:45:43 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[I often get asked about cheap power banks with hard-to-believe claims. Well, I bought one and tested it. Here's my buying advice.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[I ignored Apple's battery advice for months - here's how my iPhone 17 Pro Max performs now]]></title><link>https://www.zdnet.com/article/ignored-apple-battery-advice-on-iphone-the-result/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 02:42:00 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[I did everything Apple tells you not to do with my iPhone 17 Pro Max, and waited.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[Discord's new age ID rules are driving users away - here's where they're headed]]></title><link>https://www.zdnet.com/article/discord-age-verification-requirement/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 02:37:00 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[Unverified users will soon need to upload a video selfie or official ID to remove age restrictions.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[Ford Says Electric Vehicle Losses Will Continue for 3 More Years]]></title><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2026/02/10/business/ford-earnings-electric-vehicles.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 02:34:58 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[Ford Motor reported a big loss for 2025 because of its troubled electric vehicle division, which it has significantly scaled back.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[Can you trust LastPass in 2026? Inside the multimillion-dollar quest to rebuild its security culture]]></title><link>https://www.zdnet.com/article/lastpass-2026-rebuilding-trust-ceo-interview/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 02:34:08 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[After a string of high-profile breaches, the password manager's new CEO says security is now at the 'very heart' of what it does.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[The best streaming service you're not taking advantage of (but probably have access to)]]></title><link>https://www.zdnet.com/article/kanopy-free-streaming-service-signup/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 02:32:00 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[Kanopy offers many popular shows and movies found in paid streaming services. Here's how to sign up for it.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[Your Roku just got 9 more channels to watch for free - including a big one for Pokemon]]></title><link>https://www.zdnet.com/article/roku-free-upgrade-9-channels/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 02:31:00 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[Roku adds another lineup of more channels to its free Live TV lineup. Here's how to access the new shows.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[The Toyota Highlander is now a three-row electric SUV with 320 miles of range]]></title><link>https://www.theverge.com/transportation/875906/toyota-highlander-ev-suv-range-specs</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 02:30:00 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[Toyota unveiled the new 2027 Highlander, a fully redesigned midsize SUV that marks the brand's first three-row electric vehicle for the US market and the first Toyota EV assembled in America. It's a familiar name - Toyota has been selling gas Highlanders for over 20 years - with an all-new powertrain aimed directly at one of the most popular vehicle segments in the market today. To say this is Toyota's best chance to best its EV rivals would be an understatement.
The announcement comes at a tumultuous time for the world's best-selling automaker. Toyota's strategy of emphasizing hybrid vehicles over pure battery-electric ones seems to have b …
Read the full story at The Verge.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[I tried to save $1,200 by vibe coding for free - and quickly regretted it]]></title><link>https://www.zdnet.com/article/free-ai-coding-tool-goose-vs-claude-code-not-ready/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 02:17:23 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[I wanted to believe this free AI coding tool could replace Claude Code. But it isn't ready for prime time yet.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[How to disable ACR on your TV - and why it makes such a big difference doing so]]></title><link>https://www.zdnet.com/article/how-to-disable-acr-tv/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 02:13:47 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[Your Samsung, LG, and even TCL TV comes with risks you should know about. Here's how to avoid one of the biggest.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[Elon Musk Wants to Build an A.I. Satellite Factory on the Moon]]></title><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2026/02/10/technology/elon-musk-lunar-factory.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 02:04:43 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[In a meeting with employees at his company xAI, Mr. Musk revealed a vision for a facility that includes a giant catapult to launch his satellites into space.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[Watch YouTube TV? This simple trick can knock $80 off your bill - here's how]]></title><link>https://www.zdnet.com/article/youtube-tv-discount-save-80-bill-4-months/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 02:03:00 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[A few clicks are all it takes for you to get a discount on your YouTube TV subscription for the next 4 months.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[How I turned my Android tablet into a dedicated e-reader (and it works on iPad, too)]]></title><link>https://www.zdnet.com/article/how-to-turn-ipad-android-tablet-into-e-reader/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 02:00:46 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[There's no need for a separate device when your iPad or Android tablet can hold your whole reading library.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA['I lost two hours of my day' - the harsh reality of AI in the workplace]]></title><link>https://www.zdnet.com/article/confidence-in-ai-tools-among-workers-plunged-why-and-what-to-do-about-it/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 01:55:46 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[AI adoption is up while employee confidence in the technology is down. A ManpowerGroup report explains why.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[This handheld e-reader has effectively replaced my Kindle, and the price is hard to beat]]></title><link>https://www.zdnet.com/article/durobo-krono-e-reader-tablet-review/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 01:45:57 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[The DuRobo Krono is one of the few e-reading devices that fits comfortably in my pants.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[This 77-inch LG OLED TV from last year is 50% off at Best Buy - and I highly recommend it]]></title><link>https://www.zdnet.com/article/best-buy-lg-b5-oled-tv-deal/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 01:45:00 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[Looking for a budget-friendly OLED upgrade? The LG B5 at half price is one of the best deals ahead of Presidents' Day.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[My simple tweaks that bring dead-sounding headphones back to life - Sony and Bose included]]></title><link>https://www.zdnet.com/article/3-easy-ways-to-upgrade-your-headphones-free/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 01:42:00 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[Are your headphones feeling old? Consider these tweaks before upgrading.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[These Windows 11 PCs are getting a free Bluetooth upgrade - here's how to use it properly]]></title><link>https://www.zdnet.com/article/windows-bluetooth-le-audio-sharing-auracast/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 01:36:00 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[Both your laptop and hearing device must be compatible with Bluetooth LE Audio to use the latest connectivity feature.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[I've tested dozens of E Ink tablets, but this Android checks the most boxes for me]]></title><link>https://www.zdnet.com/article/boox-note-air5-c-review/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 01:34:45 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[The Boox Note Air5 C tablet has deeply customizable note-taking features, making it ideal for planning lists and journaling.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[FDA refuses to review Moderna's mRNA flu vaccine]]></title><link>https://arstechnica.com/health/2026/02/fda-refuses-to-review-modernas-mrna-flu-vaccine/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 01:21:12 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[The move comes amid RFK Jr.'s relentless efforts to enact his anti-vaccine agenda.]]></description></item></channel></rss>