<?xml version="1.0"?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>AI News</title><link>https://ainews.ukiuni.com/</link><description>AI related news</description><item><title><![CDATA[Grab this 75-inch Insignia QLED TV for less than $500 at Best Buy]]></title><link>https://www.zdnet.com/article/best-buy-presidents-day-insignia-qf-tv-deal/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 14:31:16 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[Looking to upgrade your home theater on a tight budget? Right now during Best Buy's Presidents' Day sale, you can save $250 on the 75-inch Insignia QF Series QLED TV which brings the price to just $400.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[You can save $1,100 on the HP Omen 17 at Best Buy, and it's a powerhouse laptop]]></title><link>https://www.zdnet.com/article/best-buy-hp-omen-17-gaming-laptop-deal/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 14:28:00 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[The recent rise of RAM and GPU prices has made it hard to find good gaming laptop deals. This one's an exception.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[The iPhone Air MagSafe battery is cheaper than ever right now]]></title><link>https://www.engadget.com/deals/the-iphone-air-magsafe-battery-is-cheaper-than-ever-right-now-144516705.html?src=rss</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 14:26:25 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[We found the iPhone Air to have a pretty decent battery life for such a thin-and-light phone, somewhere in the region of 27 hours if you’re continuously streaming video. But it's still a phone, arguably your most used device on a daily basis, so you may need to top it up during the day if you're using it constantly. That’s where Apple’s iPhone Air MagSafe battery pack comes in, and it’s currently on sale for $79.
 

 
 
This accessory only works with the iPhone Air, but much like the phone it attaches to, it’s extremely slim at 7.5mmm, so crucially doesn’t add so much bulk when attached that it defeats the point of having a thin phone in the first place. The MagSafe Battery isn’t enormous at 3,149mAh (enough to add an extra 65 percent of charge to the Air), but it can wirelessly charge the AirPods Pro 3 as well, making it an even more useful travel companion. You can also charge your iPhone while charging the battery pack.
 
At its regular price of $99, the MagSafe battery pack is an admittedly pricey add-on to what is already an expensive phone, but for $20 off it’s well worth considering what Engadget’s Sam Rutherford called an "essential accessory" for some users in his iPhone Air review.
 
Many Apple loyalists will always insist on having first-party accessories for their iPhone, but there are plenty of third-party MagSafe chargers out there too, a lot of them considerably cheaper than Apple’s lineup. Be sure to check out our guide for those. 
 
Follow @EngadgetDeals on X for the latest tech deals and buying advice.
This article originally appeared on Engadget at https://www.engadget.com/deals/the-iphone-air-magsafe-battery-is-cheaper-than-ever-right-now-144516705.html?src=rss]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[I disabled this Google Pixel core to free up to 10GB of storage space - how it works]]></title><link>https://www.zdnet.com/article/how-to-disable-aicore-free-storage/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 14:10:00 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[If your Pixel phone is running out of storage space, there's one thing you can do to reclaim GBs: disable a single service.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[How an ‘icepocalypse’ raises more questions about Meta’s biggest data center project]]></title><link>https://www.theverge.com/science/876555/meta-data-center-winter-power-outages-storm-ice</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 14:06:11 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[Donna Collins lives about 20 miles from where Meta's biggest data center is being built, in a house her family has lived in for five generations. Construction has thrown the small agricultural community in North Louisiana into the spotlight as a high-profile example of how the infrastructure behind generative AI could impact nearby residents. 
For Collins, this place is "a little piece of heaven." "It's all I've ever known as a home. It's quiet. It's rural. It is beautiful," she says. "We can't imagine the changes that are coming."
The region was particularly hard-hit by the recent cold snap that knocked out power for hundreds of thousands …
Read the full story at The Verge.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[Process Zero is even better with a little processing on the side]]></title><link>https://www.theverge.com/tech/875919/halide-mark-iii-process-zero-hands-on</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[Backlit is back. | Photo: Allison Johnson / The Verge	

Something happens every time I try to use an iPhone camera like a real camera.
Here's how it goes: I shoot RAW in addition to the default HEIC output, and since I have the RAW file I might as well edit it to my taste. And if I'm going to do that, I want to use Lightroom on my MacBook. You know, real software. Then I remember: iPhone photos hate real software. Moving image files between devices is mysterious. If I Airdrop them to my Macbook will the HDR gain map tag along? Why do my photos always come out of Lightroom looking different than my edit? Where did that gain map go? I lack the patience to find out, so I just live with what my phon …
Read the full story at The Verge.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[Pokopia turns the Pokémon world into a relaxing, human-free paradise]]></title><link>https://www.theverge.com/games/876285/pokemon-pokopia-hands-on-preview</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[Though catching monsters and making them fight have always been core elements of the Pokémon brand, spinoffs like the Pokémon Snap and Detective Pikachu series have stood out by approaching the franchise from different angles. In different (and often small) ways, recent mainline Pokémon titles like Sword / Shield, Scarlet / Violet, and Legends: Z-A have acknowledged that there are some players who would much rather spend their time hanging out and taking pictures with their monster friends.
That leisurely approach to enjoying the Pokémon world doesn't exactly gel with the main games' focus on becoming a competitive champion, but it is exact …
Read the full story at The Verge.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[Pokemon Pokopia is so damn cozy]]></title><link>https://www.engadget.com/gaming/nintendo/pokemon-pokopia-is-so-damn-cozy-140000954.html?src=rss</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[Pokémon Pokopia can be described as a pocket monster-themed take on Animal Crossing with a hint of Stardew Valley thrown in for good measure. And if you're like me, that alone is probably enough to sell you on the game. However, after getting a chance to play a preview of it for around half an hour, it became immediately clear that the game's coziness levels are off the charts, but it also offers some fun twists on the genre.
Co-developed by The Pokémon Company, GAME FREAK and KOEI TECMO, instead of playing as a generic trainer, you take control of a lonely Ditto who wakes up in a cave only to be greeted by Professor Tangrowth, the last surviving inhabitant of what used to be a bustling town. While the professor might look like an extra-large version of the original pokémon with glasses, its role is to guide you as you rebuild and hopefully repopulate the surrounding area.
One of the best things about Pokopia is actually being able to talk to the other 'mons.
Nintendo

As a Ditto, you naturally have the ability to transform into other Pokémon, though the process is sort of incomplete, meaning you can only learn one skill from the monsters you befriend instead of their entire moveset like in the mainline games. This is where the first twist on the traditional life sim comes in. Instead of crafting them or earning money to buy tools, you can transform into other Pokémon (like Lapras or Dragonite) to use their abilities to traverse obstacles or shape the world around you. For example, turning into a Squirtle lets you shoot a water gun that will revitalize dry patches or thirsty plants, while transforming into a Scyther lets you slice through objects similar to the HM Cut. 
From there, you can use these skills to do things like create clusters of shrubs that will serve as homes for other Pokémon, allowing you to entice fellow creatures to return to the once desolate landscape. Another twist I really appreciate is that after appearing, new monsters will give you quests or just hang out. They will even talk and respond, and I don't mean like the 8-bit cries from other Pokémon games. They speak in full sentences, which is a wonderful departure from previous titles that really gives you the feeling that you're making friends and rebuilding a community instead of just being on a crusade to catch them all. 



The Stardew Valley part of the equation comes into play after you leave the first tutorial area and you come upon an abandoned Pokémon Center that's in dire need of a renovation. You can do things like collect materials and do more quests to clean up the area to eventually turn the building in the heart of the town. Unfortunately, that's where my preview ended, aside from quickly hopping into a multiplayer session where I was able to see a much more developed village, complete with multiple buildings, roads and benches. You know, all the sorts of things you used to furnish and decorate your island with in Animal Crossing. 
This gave me a nice glimpse at just how many things you can build in Pokopia and how easy it is to visit other people's towns. However, it didn't answer some of my bigger questions about the game, like what's the deal with Peakychu and Mosslax, whom we've seen before in previous trailers. Are they just one-off versions of existing ‘mons with unusual typings (i.e. ghost and grass) only for this game, or are they going to be a bigger part of the Pokémon world going forward? Perhaps more importantly, it was hard to tell if there will be any sort of PVE content like The Mines or Skull Cavern in Stardew Valley. I'm really hoping there is because it seems like Ditto's abilities could translate quite seamlessly to spelunking or battling your way through dungeons in search of rare items or building materials. 
I love how derpy Ditto looks when it transforms into other Pokémon. 
Nintendo

That said, just being able to build a community of friendly monsters while injecting life back into a forgotten town has good vibes radiating from every corner. So if you need a super cozy game to keep you busy this winter/spring, Pokémon Pokopia is shaping up to be the digital version of a fluffy blanket and a cup of hot chocolate filled to the brim with all of your favorite 'mons. 
Pokémon Pokopia is available for pre-order now, with official sales slated for March 5.

This article originally appeared on Engadget at https://www.engadget.com/gaming/nintendo/pokemon-pokopia-is-so-damn-cozy-140000954.html?src=rss]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[Is spyware hiding on your phone? How to find out and remove it - fast]]></title><link>https://www.zdnet.com/article/spyware-hiding-on-phone-how-to-find-remove-fast/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[Think your phone is acting strange? It may be infected with spyware. Here are the warning signs and and how you can stop it.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[The 512GB Samsung P9 microSD Express card is 33 percent off]]></title><link>https://www.engadget.com/deals/the-512gb-samsung-p9-microsd-express-card-is-33-percent-off-143849572.html?src=rss</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 13:45:38 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[MicroSD Express cards are still a little hard to find, considering they're pretty new and only really started becoming popular last year once the Switch 2 came out. These upgraded versions of microSD cards are the only ones compatible with the Switch 2 for expanding its storage, os if you're already starting to feel the crunch on your console, it's worth picking one up. Samsung's P9 microSD Express card is on sale right now — you can grab the 512GB version of $80, which is 33 percent off and one of the best prices we've seen.
 
The P9 boasts transfer speeds of up to 800MB/s, making moving games to the card that much faster. As for load times, in our testing we found that any microSD Express, the standard the Switch 2 requires, will offer roughly the same performance. This format is pretty new, so there aren't a ton of cards on the market. As such, the P9 makes our list of best microSD cards for the Nintendo Switch 2.
 
The P9 microSD Express is also compatible with the Steam Deck or any other gaming console that accepts the format, as well as cameras and more.
 

 
 
Follow @EngadgetDeals on X for the latest tech deals and buying advice.
This article originally appeared on Engadget at https://www.engadget.com/deals/the-512gb-samsung-p9-microsd-express-card-is-33-percent-off-143849572.html?src=rss]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[The Apple Watch Series 11 drops to $299 ahead of Presidents' Day]]></title><link>https://www.engadget.com/deals/the-apple-watch-series-11-drops-to-299-ahead-of-presidents-day-151616891.html?src=rss</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 13:22:56 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[Whether you're one of the few people still keeping up with New Year's resolutions or just want an upgraded smartwatch, now is a good time to get an Apple Watch now that you can save with Presidents' Day deals. Currently, the Apple Watch Series 11 is on sale for $299, down from $399. The 25 percent discount brings the 2025 model back down to its record-low price.
 
We named the Apple Watch Series 11 as our choice for best smartwatch overall. It scored a 90 in our review thanks to its 24 hours-plus of battery life and a thin, light design that's easy to wear. It also offers new health metrics, including Apple's hypertension alerts system and Sleep Score. 
 
The Apple Watch Series 11 deal is available on the 42mm case with a small/medium band. It also only includes GPS and four colorways: the Jet Black and Space Gray aluminum cases with a Black sport band, the Rose Gold aluminum case with a Light Blush sport band and the Silver aluminum case with a Purple Fog sport band.
 

 
 
Follow @EngadgetDeals on X for the latest tech deals and buying advice.
This article originally appeared on Engadget at https://www.engadget.com/deals/the-apple-watch-series-11-drops-to-299-ahead-of-presidents-day-151616891.html?src=rss]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[El Paso flights resume after Mexican cartel drones reportedly trigger airspace closure]]></title><link>https://www.theverge.com/transportation/877019/el-paso-airport-faa-flights-grounded-airspace-special-security</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 13:11:15 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[The Federal Aviation Administration has lifted its temporary closure to the airspace around El Paso International Airport in Texas, after originally saying that all flights in and out of the airport would be grounded for 10 days. No explanation for the closure was given, beyond a vague reference to "Special Security Reasons." CBS News reported the closure was "triggered by Mexican cartel drones breaching US airspace." The Department of Defense has reportedly disabled the drones, the news outlet said.
The closure was announced late on February 10th in a notice on the FAA website, and was expected to apply until February 20th. A second notice …
Read the full story at The Verge.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[How to Set Up an Apple Watch for Your Kids (2026)]]></title><link>https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-set-up-apple-watch-for-kids/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[Want to give your children an easy way to contact you—without giving them a smartphone? Family Setup on WatchOS can help.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[Mullvad VPN review: Near-total privacy with a few sacrifices]]></title><link>https://www.engadget.com/cybersecurity/vpn/mullvad-vpn-review-near-total-privacy-with-a-few-sacrifices-130000056.html?src=rss</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[Mullvad, a virtual private network (VPN) named after the Swedish word for "mole," is often recognized as one of the best VPNs for privacy. I put it on my best VPN list for exactly that reason. I've got huge respect for the extra lengths Mullvad goes to in order to ensure its user's privacy.
To give you a preview, Mullvad is one of the few VPNs — other than my normal privacy recommendation, Proton VPN — that lets users pay entirely in cash. But even Proton VPN asks for an email address to make an account and uses a few marketing cookies on its own website. Mullvad represents every account as a randomly generated 16-digit code and uses no marketing cookies whatsoever.
That's just one example of how Mullvad goes beyond the call of duty to keep users private. But while privacy is the most important aspect of a VPN alongside security, it's not the only thing that matters. For this review, I set out to investigate whether Mullvad pairs its rights-protecting bonafides with versatile, convenient and enjoyable VPN apps. Using our rigorous VPN testing procedure, I'll rate Mullvad in 11 areas. You can find a summary of my results in the table below, skip to the sections that matter most to you or just read my final advice in the conclusion.
Editor's note (2/11/26): We've overhauled our VPN coverage to provide more detailed, actionable buying advice. Going forward, we'll continue to update both our best VPN list and individual reviews (like this one) as circumstances change. Most recently, we added official scores to all of our VPN reviews. Check out how we test VPNs to learn more about the new standards we're using.

Findings at a glance
Category

   
Notes

  
Installation and UI

   
All apps share roughly the same user interface
Apps are responsive and easy to navigate, with no design choices that would threaten beginners
Lack of "fastest server" button is an issue
Browser extension is only available on Firefox and still in beta

  
Speed

   
Reasonably good average latency
Reduces download speeds by 26 percent and upload speeds by 17 percent
Speed declines are consistent and chartable
All speed metrics are quite good on nearby servers

  
Security

   
Only uses WireGuard protocol
No IP address leaks, even when switching servers
Packet test showed successful encryption

  
Pricing

   
Always costs 5 Euro per month, though prices outside Europe depend on exchange rates
No auto-renewal — membership lasts until money runs out
Can pay using cash or by purchasing scratch-off vouchers on Amazon
14 day money-back guarantee, except on cash payments

  
Bundles

   
Only app besides the VPN is the free Mullvad Browser, which removes the tracking habits of typical web browsers
Allows several smaller VPNs to use its servers in their networks

  
Privacy policy

   
No vague lines or loopholes in privacy policy
Only saves account numbers and expiration dates for each user
Uses an extremely limited range of cookies with no marketing trackers
Has undergone a total of 17 audits of different aspects of its service
Swedish police demanded customer information in 2023; Mullvad couldn't comply because the data wasn't logged

  
Virtual location change

   
Unblocked Netflix 13 out of 15 times
When it failed, virtual location was still changed

  
Server network

   
90 locations in 50 countries, majority in North America and Europe
No virtual servers whatsoever

  
Features

   
DAITA conceals traffic patterns that might let an AI identify what sites you visit
Uses quantum-resistant encryption on WireGuard
Can choose your own multihop entry and exit points
Several options for getting around nation-level firewalls
Can block ads, trackers, malware and other unwanted content using predetermined DNS block lists
Supports IPv6 traffic
Kill switch and stronger lockdown mode
Split tunneling by app

  
Customer support

   
Help center includes useful filters to find the topic
Well-written articles with good internal linking
No live chat support, but staff answers emails quickly
Can view app logs at any time

  
Background check

   
Founded in 2009 in Sweden; still owned and operated by initial founders
User account numbers were exposed in a 2023 incident, but Mullvad quickly closed the leak

  
Installing, configuring and using Mullvad
Let's start by examining how Mullvad feels as a piece of software. In this section, I'll be testing its desktop apps for Windows and Mac, its mobile apps for Android and iOS and its browser extension for Firefox. To start with the installation process, Mullvad downloads and installs in a snap on mobile. On desktop, installation requires a few more steps than is typical, but the app guides you quickly through everything.
Across the board, my only serious complaint is that there's no option for automatically choosing the fastest server. You can usually assume that the nearest one to you will be the fastest, but there's always the chance of an unusual server overload. It's a bizarre oversight for an app that otherwise goes out of its way to be usable.
Windows
Mullvad's Windows app has a slim UI that uses space efficiently without being too cramped. It doesn't give you a lot of information, such as live speed tests or data in transit, but I've mostly found that to be needless filler on VPN apps.
Speaking of needless filler, the map may be a little bigger than it needs to be, but maps on VPN clients aren't just about teaching you geography — they do a lot to make the apps more welcoming to casual users who might not otherwise fire up security software. In fact, Mullvad's UI is admirably beginner-friendly, befitting its focus on privacy for everybody rather than just the tech-savvy.
All the settings are accessed by clicking the gear in the top-right. Here, you can turn on DAITA (Mullvad's defense against AI traffic scanning), activate multihop and control Mullvad's other features. There are also some quality-of-life features for the UI itself, such as whether it remains pinned to the taskbar or operates as a standalone window. Some options, especially under the VPN settings tab, are a bit technical, but don't need to be touched for a good experience.
Mac
Mullvad's macOS app is quite similar to its Windows app, both in terms of the interface and the features offered. The big difference used to be that macOS lacked split tunneling, but that's been added in a recent update. The only serious distinction now is that the Mac client can't be unpinned from the taskbar, which is just a little bothersome.
Other than that, you'll find every setting you need under the gear, just like on Windows. Similarly, connections to VPN servers happen quickly, and selecting locations from the menu is very straightforward. While connected on either app, you can click the circular arrow by your location to swap to another server in the same location — highly convenient if you're trying to unblock Netflix.
Android
Mullvad's Android app has the same nearly-perfect design approach as all its other apps. The main page has nothing on it but the connect/disconnect button, the choice of server locations, a map and the buttons for your account information and preferences. Those preferences are a manageable set of options that are almost all managed with simple on-off switches. It's all highly responsive and annoyance-free.
iOS
Mullvad's iOS app looks very similar to its apps on every other platform. The front page is kept simple, with large controls in the foreground and a map taking up most of the space. Everything else is located in the menu accessed through the gear icon at top right. Neither mobile app has the options for toggling the UI itself that the desktop apps have, but it's mostly free of quality-of-life problems to start with.
Browser extensions
Mullvad's browser extension is only compatible with Firefox. You can't actually connect to the VPN through this extension. Its main functions are to tell you whether you're connected to a Mullvad server and to connect to a SOCKS5 proxy in a Mullvad location. If you do this while connected to Mullvad through the desktop app, you'll get a second layer of protection, similar to the multi-hop feature.
The Firefox extension is a rare misfire for Mullvad — perhaps fair, since it's still in beta. Its only real feature is something that the desktop app already does perfectly well, and it looks like a software malfunction to boot. However, given Mullvad's track record, I'm confident they'll figure out what to do with it in time.
Mullvad speed test
A VPN almost always slows browsing speeds and increases latencies. It's unavoidable, given the extra steps a VPN protocol adds to the process of getting online. The trick is to find VPNs that keep the slowdown to a minimum, using a combination of regular maintenance, good planning and smart load balancing.
For this test, I used speedtest.net to check how six of Mullvad's server locations influenced three key speed metrics. Ping measures latency, the time in milliseconds (ms) that one data packet needs to travel between a client device and an ISP. Download speed measures the amount of data in Megabits that a web browser can download in one second. Upload speed tracks how much data can be uploaded in a second. We're looking for low latencies and high download and upload speeds.
Server location

   
Ping (ms)

   
Increase factor

   
Download speed (Mbps)

   
Percentage drop

   
Upload speed (Mbps)

   
Percentage drop

  
Portland, USA (unprotected)

   
15

   
—
   
58.96

   
—
   
5.85

   
—
  
Seattle, USA (fastest location)

   
23

   
1.5x

   
55.07

   
6.6

   
5.51

   
5.8

  
Montreal, Canada

   
165

   
11.0x

   
44.28

   
24.9

   
4.62

   
21.0

  
Fortaleza, Brazil

   
307

   
20.5x

   
40.96

   
30.5

   
4.65

   
20.5

  
Prague, Czechia

   
368

   
24.5x

   
43.17

   
26.8

   
5.47

   
6.5

  
Lagos, Nigeria

   
528

   
35.2x

   
37.41

   
36.6

   
4.61

   
21.2

  
Bangkok, Thailand

   
473

   
31.5x

   
39.76

   
32.6

   
4.13

   
29.4

  
Average

   
311

   
20.7x

   
43.44

   
26.3

   
4.83

   
17.4

  
I'll start with the bad news: the tests didn't exactly make Mullvad look like a speed demon. Its speeds have gone up and down in the years I've been using it, and right now they appear to be on the downswing. If you use locations all around Mullvad's server network, you can expect your download speeds to decrease by about 26 percent and your upload speeds to decline by 17 percent.
However, it's important to put those numbers in perspective. First, Mullvad's numbers aren't markedly worse than the ones I got when testing CyberGhost. Its speeds are average, but by definition, most things are average. Its average worldwide latency is actually better than Surfshark, the current champion of download and upload speeds.
It's also nice that Mullvad's speed drops follow a predictable curve. Lots of VPNs have unexpectedly sharp declines in certain locations, frequently in Africa. By contrast, Mullvad's speed decreases pretty much as a direct function of how far from the server you are. This not only makes speed drops easier to plan around, but also means you can expect very good speeds on nearby servers.
This property of being fastest on servers near the user is another sign of Mullvad's focus on its core privacy mission. If anonymity is your main reason for using a VPN, it doesn't matter what your IP address is, so long as it's not your real one. Using a nearby Mullvad server should guarantee you an internet connection that's both fast and private.
Mullvad security test
To be secure, a VPN has to check two critical boxes. It must provide you with a secondary IP address without leaking your real one, and it must encrypt your communications with its servers so your activity can't be traced. In the sections below, I'll see whether Mullvad meets those requirements.
VPN protocols
VPNs use protocols to mediate between end devices, ISPs and their own servers. The first step is to ensure that the service you're considering uses protocols that have expert confidence. Mullvad has kindly made this step easy for me by using only WireGuard on all its apps, with no OpenVPN, IKEv2 or in-house unique protocols.
There's no question that WireGuard is a solid protocol. It uses the ChaCha20 stream cipher for symmetric encryption and Poly1305 for authentication, both uncrackable with current technology. Mullvad has even added its own fix for WireGuard's one flaw, its need to save static IP addresses — the Mullvad implementation is set up to delete the IP address if it goes 10 minutes without being used.
Even so, it's unfortunate to lose the ability to change protocols, which is one of the most common steps for troubleshooting a VPN connection. I understand Mullvad's reasoning for cutting out OpenVPN (it claims the cryptography isn't strong enough) but don't agree. It's one of this provider's few unforced errors.
Leak test
There's a straightforward test to determine if your VPN is leaking. Load up any website that shows your IP address — I personally use ipleak.net — and see what IP and location it reveals without your VPN active. Then activate the VPN and refresh the page. If you see your real IP address anywhere, your VPN is leaking.
I ran that test on five Mullvad servers. Each time, the website showed me the IP address of the VPN server, concealing my real one. To keep things simple, I ran the initial tests with IPv6 blocked via the Mullvad client. When I turned it on and tried again, the IPv6 traffic didn't leak any more than the IPv4 did. I also saw no signs of WebRTC leaks. Unless you set up a custom DNS server, Mullvad also uses its own DNS, which remains entirely within the VPN tunnel.
I had one more leak test to try. Frequently, VPNs are leak-proof when maintaining a connection to one server but drop encryption when switching between servers. That problem is why I ultimately couldn't recommend Norton VPN. Luckily for me, Mullvad has a button that lets you shuffle to another server in the same location, so I used that to see if it stayed leak-proof.
As you can see in the screenshot, Mullvad jumped seamlessly from one server to another without showing my real location in-between. On a practical level, that's enough for me to declare Mullvad leak-proof.
Encryption test
For one final experiment, I used the WireShark packet sniffer to see whether the data Mullvad sent from my computer to my ISP was encrypted. After capturing a few packets, I was gratified to see that they were totally unreadable to interlopers. Most established VPNs pass this test, but it's still important for due diligence.
How much does Mullvad cost?
Mullvad's pricing structure is one of the most unusual things about it. This is normally the section where I untangle 47 different Pro+ and Business- accounts that are all sold at three different durations. Mullvad couldn't be further from that. It costs 5 Euro a month — that’s it. Each 5-Euro subscription can be used on five devices at once.
It manages payments through a system inspired by parking meters. When you sign up for Mullvad, you'll buy as much time as you want. That time will count down until it expires, unless you top it up with more 5-Euro payments. If you run out of money, Mullvad won't charge you a new subscription fee because you didn't tell it not to. It'll just stop working until you pay again. Every payment also comes with a 14-day money-back guarantee, except for payments made in cash.
The only real complexity in the process is that Mullvad always figures out its prices in Euro, so outside the EU, the cost per month is affected by exchange rates. If you happen to live in a country where the government's economic policy shuttles between capricious and arbitrary, you might want to grab a few months in advance.
The other most interesting thing about Mullvad's pricing is the options you can use to pay. For maximum privacy, you can pay with cash using the payment token you'll find on your account page. Note that this is not the same as your account number. To find it, log into your dashboard on Mullvad.net, click Add time to your account in the left-hand bar, then click the button labeled Cash and scroll down. Make your cash payment by writing the token on an envelope and mailing it to Sweden (full instructions here).
You can also get untraceable Mullvad vouchers by paying cash at participating retail locations. Most of them are in Europe, but you can order them from Amazon. While your payment to Amazon won't be private, the voucher can't be linked directly to your VPN account, since the actual number is hidden behind a scratch-off panel. It's actually pretty ingenious.
Of course, you can also pay using any of the normal methods, including credit cards, cryptocurrency and bank wires (though not PayPal). But the more private methods are always there for people who need them.
Mullvad side apps and bundles
Mullvad is that rare VPN that's still content to be a VPN and not an all-inclusive security suite. No shade to NordVPN or Surfshark, whose extra features are generally quite good, but it's nice to see at least one of the top providers staying focused.
Although Mullvad doesn't have any partners that sell their products alongside its VPN, it does have several partnerships with other VPNs who use its network as the basis for their own products. MalwareBytes Privacy VPN, Mozilla VPN, Tailscale and Obscura can all be considered Mullvad side apps if you squint.
Mullvad Browser
Mullvad's only product other than the VPN is Mullvad Browser, which is free to download and works on Windows, macOS and Linux. Mullvad Browser works in the background, blocking common methods of browser fingerprinting that can be used to deduce your identity even when you have a VPN running.
For example, it automatically reports your time zone as UTC, disguises personal preferences like font and window size, scrambles information sent by APIs and conceals your browser version and computer operating system. It's also in private mode by default, which doesn't hide what your ISP sees but is useful for concealing your activity from other people that might use your computer.
Close-reading Mullvad's privacy policy
Since privacy is Mullvad's main selling point, this section is even more important than usual. Loopholes in the privacy policy of the privacy VPN would be deeply ironic. Fortunately, Mullvad's privacy policy backs up its high-flying rhetoric. It's a short, pointed and readable document with no problems I could discern. Mullvad has no parent company or subsidiary it might use as a loophole, and no clauses in its policy are left open to interpretation. It's a masterpiece of the privacy-policy genre.
The document is actually three policies: a privacy policy, a no-logging policy and a cookie policy. The privacy policy lists all the times Mullvad might collect data about a user. That's exactly two situations — using financial information to process payments (which will be entirely anonymous if you use cash or a voucher) and using your email address to track support tickets you open. That's it.
The no-logging policy is a bit longer, but mostly because it's explaining exactly how Mullvad manages to run a VPN service with so little information on individual users. For each account, it stores a number and an expiration date, plus public keys and tunnel addresses if you're using WireGuard (deleted at most 10 minutes after your session ends). Everything else is completely anonymized. Mullvad even claims that its 500,000 or so user accounts could have been created by the same user 500,000 times, which I suppose is one way to spend 2.5 million Euro.
The cookie policy is the shortest because Mullvad uses exactly five cookies. One saves your login status in your browser, one saves your language preferences, one protects its site from being used in a specific kind of forgery hack and the other two are for handling Stripe payments.
Independent privacy audits
Mullvad corroborates its privacy policy with regular audits of various aspects of its service. Currently, there are 17 audits listed on its website, including four infrastructure audits by Cure53. All of its apps have been separately audited and found to be solid. It has been a couple of years since the last full infrastructure audit in 2024, but given how many other targeted reviews Mullvad has gone through since then, it's hard to be too upset about the pause.
In 2023, Mullvad achieved the holy grail of VPN privacy: being ordered by subpoena to turn over customer information and not being able to comply because that information didn't exist. Nothing compares to a VPN's privacy being tested in the wild like this.
Can Mullvad change your virtual location?
Sometimes, a VPN appears to be working, but still reveals your real location to websites. Netflix is a useful proxy for this. To unblock a streaming site like Netflix, a VPN needs to change your virtual location while not appearing to do so — if Netflix sees any hint of VPN traffic, you'll get blocked with the hated proxy error. I used five different locations to check whether Mullvad is up to the streaming task.
Server location

   
Unblocked Netflix?

   
Changed content?

  
Vancouver, Canada

   
3/3

   
3/3

  
Gothenberg, Sweden

   
2/3

   
2/3

  
Istanbul, Turkey

   
3/3

   
3/3

  
Johannesburg, South Africa

   
3/3

   
3/3

  
Singapore, Singapore

   
2/3

   
2/3

  
Mullvad did well for streaming, but it didn't manage a perfect score like its fellow anti-establishment VPN Windscribe did. Two of the 15 servers I tested failed to unblock Netflix, one in Singapore and one in Mullvad's hometown of Gothenburg. I also had trouble logging into Netflix while connected to a Vancouver server, though that server did unblock the site consistently once I got inside.
In Mullvad's defense, no location failed more than once. It's completely possible to get good streaming performance out of this VPN; you just have to be willing to click the server refresh button a few times. Privacy is still the main use case for Mullvad, but it's fine for streaming too.
Investigating Mullvad's server network
Mullvad has 90 server locations in 50 countries and territories. Unusually for a VPN, users can choose between all 590 of its total servers, including several in each location. There's even a list on its website that shows you the status of every server.
Mullvad does not use virtual server locations, so every server is physically located in the place where it claims to be. Here's how they're distributed.
Region

   
Countries with servers

   
Total server locations

  
North America

   
3
   
25

  
South America

   
5
   
6
  
Europe

   
29

   
41

  
Africa

   
2
   
2
  
Middle East

   
2
   
2
  
Asia

   
7
   
8
  
Oceania

   
2
   
6
  
Total

   
50

   
90

  
Over half the countries with servers are in Europe and over two-thirds of the cities with servers are in either Europe or North America. That lopsided network is a limitation of Mullvad's refusal to use virtual server locations, since its real servers have to be concentrated in nations developed enough to host data centers. With an all-real network, it's easier to tell which servers will give you the fastest performance, but you can't simulate as much of the world as you can with larger services like ExpressVPN.
The good news is that there's at least two real server locations on every continent. Mullvad has a surprisingly robust presence in South America and two bare-metal servers in Africa, which is more than some other VPNs have. In the end, though, the best application of Mullvad is to protect the online privacy of users in North America, Europe and eastern Asia.
Extra features of Mullvad
Most of Mullvad's features are augmentations to the VPN itself, rather than side options that do other things. Some of them are bread-and-butter, like the kill switch and split tunneling, but a few you won't find anywhere else. Note beforehand that Mullvad does not support port forwarding, so if you depend on that for your torrenting, try another VPN.
DAITA AI defenses
Mullvad's most novel feature is a recent one. DAITA, which stands for Defense against AI-guided Traffic Analysis, can be toggled on and off in the Mullvad app. According to Mullvad, certain patterns in how browsers communicate with websites can be analyzed by AI to reveal the truth behind encrypted internet history. DAITA hides those packets by filling communications with background noise so the AI won't know what's real.
DAITA is a laudably forward-looking feature, but as Mullvad itself admits, it will make your browsing speeds slower and drain your battery. I recommend only using it for activities you really want to hide.
Quantum resistance
Mullvad's desktop apps establish quantum-proof WireGuard tunnels by default. Quantum computing isn't yet a threat to WireGuard, but it may become dangerous in the future, so Mullvad is getting ahead of the problem (along with a few other services like NordVPN). When quantum resistance is active, Mullvad encapsulates its keys using the current standard mechanism, ML-KEM.
Anti-censorship
If you find yourself in a country where government censorship makes it hard to access the internet, Mullvad has options that might help. These anti-censorship features can be used to get around firewalls that block visible VPN traffic. You have several options, including changing your WireGuard port, randomizing your port number, disguising your VPN traffic as an ordinary HTTPS connection or using an obfuscated Shadowsocks proxy.
Mullvad's anti-censorship involves more features than most VPNs have in this area. This makes it a bit less user-friendly, but a lot more likely to work. If you're new to getting around censorship, Mullvad's help center has a helpful page about using its anti-censor settings.
Multihop
Many VPNs offer a double-hop connection that routes your traffic through two servers instead of one, adding a redundant layer of encryption in case one server malfunctions. Mullvad pulls ahead of the competition (except Surfshark, which also does this) by allowing you to choose your entry and exit servers. When you activate the multihop option and open the server list, you'll be prompted to pick two locations instead of one.
This means you can select an entry server that's close to you and an exit server in any country whose location you want to spoof, letting you fine-tune your own performance. It's way nicer than being railroaded into certain paths.
DNS content blockers
Mullvad includes six blocklists that can keep you or your family members from looking at unwanted content: ads, trackers, malware, gambling, adult content and social media. These lists can't be customized like Windscribe's R.O.B.E.R.T. blocks can, so you're limited to just turning them on and off.
IPv6 support
The internet is gradually transitioning from the old IPv4 standard over to IPv6, which will allow many more addresses to be shared out. Mullvad is one of a few VPNs looking ahead to the IPv6 era. You can leave it to block all IPv6 traffic, but if you do need IPv6 for any reason, you can enable it while still being connected to a Mullvad server.
Kill switch and lockdown mode
Mullvad comes with two features that protect against unexpectedly losing your VPN defenses. The first is a kill switch, a common VPN option that cuts off internet access if the VPN tunnel ever fails. This simple measure helps guard against accidental leaks.
Lockdown mode is the stronger option. While it's active, you will be unable to get on the internet unless you connect to a Mullvad server first. This will remain true if you turn the connection off yourself and even if you quit the app.
Split tunneling
Split tunneling is available on Mullvad's apps for every system except iOS. It lets you send some apps outside the VPN tunnel so they get online with your normal IP address. It's helpful if you have some apps that don't work with the VPN active — this is common with online banking, as an example. Another common application is to protect a torrenting client in the background while using your browser unprotected for better speeds.
Mullvad customer support options
Mullvad makes two forms of support available in the app. You can report a problem by going to Settings -> Support -> Report a problem, typing your question (requested to be in either English or Swedish, though they'd probably be able to read a question run through Google Translate) and optionally providing your email. You can also view the app's logs at any time, which can be useful to help a technician diagnose your problem.
If you'd rather search for a solution at your own pace, you can go to that same page and click FAQs and Guides instead. This opens the help center in a browser.
I love Mullvad's approach to laying out its FAQs. Instead of crowding topics into five or six categories and making you guess whether your problem falls under setup, usage or troubleshooting, Mullvad gives you a set of dropdown filters to narrow down the articles which might relate to your problem.
By the time you've named which device, OS and protocol you're dealing with, you won’t have many articles left to sift through. There is an annoying tendency for certain sets of filters to reduce the number of surfaced links to zero, but for those cases, there's a search bar that also works well.
The articles themselves are good enough that I referred to them several times while writing this review. Some of them are a bit overlong, but they're diligent about including both internal and external links to get you where you're going fast.
Live support experience
This is normally where I cover how it feels to get live chat support from the VPN I'm reviewing. However, Mullvad doesn't have live chat support. That's unfortunate, although it's still better than Windscribe's approach of forcing you to banter with a sarcastic robot. Instead, I sent a question via email to Mullvad's support team, and got a response within 24 hours.
Mullvad background check
Mullvad was founded in 2009 in Sweden. It's still owned and operated by its original founders. According to a detailed timeline on its website, its 16-year history has been as uneventful as any user could ask for, with not much changing except updates to stay on the technological leading edge. The only controversy mentioned in Mullvad's own materials is the 2023 police raid of its headquarters, which (as I covered in the privacy section) only makes them look better.
So as not to take Mullvad at its word, I scoured the last 16 years of news items and user reports to search for any other blemishes on its record. Based on that research, I found no reason to doubt Mullvad's honesty about its location, owners or team.
I found just one leak that wasn't noted on Mullvad's own site. In 2023, a security research group called ZATAZ alleged that it found anonymized information on Mullvad users saved on an Internet Archive page, including account numbers (linked article is in French). According to ZATAZ, Mullvad contacted the Archive and got the page deleted.
To my mind, the only mistake Mullvad made in response to the ZATAZ allegations was not making a public statement about the incident. I can see why they didn't think it was a big deal, since even logging into someone else's Mullvad account wouldn't show you their browsing history, but it's always better to communicate about these things.
Final verdict
Mullvad is a VPN that knows what it wants to be and achieves that goal with flying colors. It's not trying to be an everything app — it does privacy and does it well. That's not to say it has nothing going on outside the VPN itself, as its DNS blockers, AI defenses and split tunneling all work smoothly. But if you want a VPN that's not ashamed to be a VPN, Mullvad is the right choice.
Of course, it has its own compromises. It's solidly in the middle of the speed pack and occasionally trips up when unblocking streaming sites. The lack of any protocols other than WireGuard grates on me a bit, since it reduces the user's options for troubleshooting. With all that said, those are minor hiccups on a VPN that does such a thorough job keeping you anonymous online.
This article originally appeared on Engadget at https://www.engadget.com/cybersecurity/vpn/mullvad-vpn-review-near-total-privacy-with-a-few-sacrifices-130000056.html?src=rss]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[T-Mobile will live translate regular phone calls without an app]]></title><link>https://www.theverge.com/tech/877008/t-mobile-live-translation-languages-ai-network</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 12:35:00 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[Even an old flip phone should be able to use T-Mobile’s Live Translation. | Illustration: Alex Castro / The Verge	

T-Mobile is preparing to test a new AI feature that translates live phone calls into more than 50 languages. Live Translation is launching in beta "this Spring," according to a press release, with registration for eligible T-Mobile customers available starting today.
"Some of the biggest barriers wireless customers face are the simplest ones - like being able to understand each other," said T-Mobile CEO Srini Gopalan. "By bringing real-time AI directly into our network, we're delivering more than connectivity - turning conversations into community, starting with Live Translation."

Enabling it at the network level means users don't need spe …
Read the full story at The Verge.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[Is surprise box-office hit Iron Lung the future of ‘video game films’?]]></title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/games/2026/feb/11/pushing-buttons-hit-film-iron-lung-youtube-markiplier</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 12:30:05 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[The YouTube gaming star’s weird and divisive adaptation of his obscure horror film is a game within a film about a game – and hints at new directions for storytelling
• Don’t get Pushing Buttons delivered to your inbox? Sign up here
Something weird struck me early on while watching the movie Iron Lung, which has so far taken $32m at the box office, despite being a grungy low-budget sci-fi thriller adapted from an independent video game few people outside of the horror gaming community have even heard of. Set after a galactic apocalypse, it follows a convict who must buy his freedom by piloting a rusty submarine through an ocean of human blood on a distant planet. Ostensibly, he’s looking for relics that may prove vital for scientific research, but what he finds is much more ghastly. So far, so strange.
The film was also written, directed and financed by one person – the YouTube gaming superstar Mark “Markiplier” Fischbach – who also stars. But that’s not the weird part, either. The weird part is that watching the film Iron Lung feels like watching Fischbach play Iron Lung the game. Maybe it’s the fact that he spends most of the movie sitting at the sub’s controls, trying to figure out how to use them correctly – like a gamer would. Maybe it’s that, as the film progresses, he has to solve a series of environmental puzzles linked by various codes, computer read-outs and little injections of narrative – just like in a video game. Long periods of the movie involve Fischbach trying to decide what to do next, the camera close up on his confused face. This is incredibly similar to watching his YouTube videos about playing Iron Lung, an experience he often found bewildering. It was the most metatextual experience I’ve had in the cinema since The Truman Show – but I’m not sure this is what Fischbach intended.
 Continue reading...]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[9 Best Cheap Laptops (2026), Tested and Reviewed]]></title><link>https://www.wired.com/gallery/best-cheap-laptops/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 12:30:00 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[From surprisingly good $300 Chromebooks to excellent $650 Windows laptops, these are the best budget laptops we’ve tested.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[The best Amazon Fire TV Stick VPNs of 2026: Expert tested and reviewed]]></title><link>https://www.zdnet.com/article/best-vpn-for-firestick/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 12:00:46 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[If you're looking for a VPN compatible with your Amazon Fire TV stick, check out my favorite VPNs that I've put to the test.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[America, it's time to think beyond leather for luxury car seats]]></title><link>https://arstechnica.com/features/2026/02/america-its-time-to-think-beyond-leather-for-luxury-car-seats/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 12:00:35 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[Some brands are already ahead of the curve, while others leave the US in the cold.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[Uber Eats adds AI assistant to help with grocery shopping]]></title><link>https://www.theverge.com/transportation/876540/uber-eats-ai-chatbot-cart-assistant-grocery-shopping</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[Uber announced a new AI feature called "Cart Assistant" for grocery shopping in its Uber Eats app.
The new feature works a couple different ways. You can use text prompts, as you would with any other AI chatbot, to ask it to build a grocery list for you. Or you can upload a picture of your shopping list and ask it to populate your cart with all your favorite items, based on your order history. You can be as generic as you - "milk, eggs, cereal" - and the bot will make a list with all your preferred brands. 
And that's just to start out. Uber says in the coming months, Cart Assistant will add more features, including "full recipe inspiratio …
Read the full story at The Verge.]]></description></item></channel></rss>