<?xml version="1.0"?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>AI News</title><link>https://ainews.ukiuni.com/</link><description>AI related news</description><item><title><![CDATA[Here’s What It’s Like to Use TurboTax’s Mobile App to File Taxes on Your Own (2026)]]></title><link>https://www.wired.com/story/whats-new-this-year-at-turbotax/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:38:00 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[Sigh. Another tax season is upon us. I filed my taxes with TurboTax, exploring its newest features and free or low-cost filing options.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[What is Pokopia? Inside the calming Pokémon game that ditches battles for gardening]]></title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/games/2026/feb/12/what-is-pokopia-developers-explain-addictive-new-pokemon-game</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:35:14 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[We explore the cosy world-building spin-off with Game Freak’s Shigeru Ohmori and his fellow developers – and learn how it began with a Pokémon-hunting dream
Pokémon is celebrating its 30th anniversary this month, and everybody knows what to expect from these games by now. The concept is simple: head into a cartoonish paradise full of whimsical creatures, capture them in red-and-white balls and assemble a team of warriors from them, before battling other aspiring Pokémon masters. But the latest entry in the series is different – a game that’s more about building than battling.
In Pokopia, a refreshingly pacific twist on the series, players are dropped into a virtual world where Pokémon are freed from their spherical prisons and happily roam their natural habitats. There’s one minor caveat – you have to create those habitats by hand, building them from what you can find.
 Continue reading...]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[The Best Kindle Accessories (2026): Cases, Page Turners, Stickers]]></title><link>https://www.wired.com/story/best-kindle-accessories/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:34:00 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[Looking to better protect your Kindle or add a little personality to your favorite e-reader? From cases and covers to page turners and even charms, this is the guide for you.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[Crypto-Funded Human Trafficking Is Exploding]]></title><link>https://www.wired.com/story/crypto-funded-human-trafficking-is-exploding/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[The use of cryptocurrency in sales of human beings for prostitution and scam compounds nearly doubled in 2025, according to a conservative estimate. Many of the deals are happening in plain sight.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[This $7,999 robot will fold (some of) your laundry]]></title><link>https://www.theverge.com/tech/877851/weave-isaac-robot-fold-laundry</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 12:59:06 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[Isaac 0 is a stationary robot with one job: folding laundry. | Image: Weave Robotics	

If you have a spare $7,999 (plus a $250 deposit), hate folding laundry, and happen to live in the Bay Area, one-and-a-half-year-old startup Weave has the robot for you: Isaac 0. 
It takes Isaac 0 around 30-90 minutes to fold a load of laundry, Weave says. That's all it does - it's stationary and needs a regular wall outlet - and it can't tackle large blankets, bed sheets, or inside-out garments. It's not fully autonomous either, with teleoperators on-hand to assist with trickier folds, though Weave says performance will improve over time. 


Today we're releasing Isaac 0: our first robot for the home.
And we made a short video for our first  …


Read the full story at The Verge.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[This free MacOS app is the secret to getting more out of your local AI models]]></title><link>https://www.zdnet.com/article/reins-is-a-gui-for-local-llms-that-simplifies-using-multiple-models/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 12:57:20 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[You should consider using Reins if you're a fan of using local LLMs on MacOS.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[How to watch local news on Roku for free - no subscription or TV antenna required]]></title><link>https://www.zdnet.com/article/how-to-watch-local-news-on-roku-free/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 12:36:00 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[The Roku Channel has hundreds of free live channels, including your local ABC, CBS, and NBC news affiliates.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[Verizon will give you a free iPhone, Samsung, or Pixel with its latest business deal - how to qualify]]></title><link>https://www.zdnet.com/article/verizon-small-business-days-sale/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 12:31:00 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[Right now at Verizon, small business owners can take advantage of great deals like free iPhone 17s, Ring camera bundles, and discounts on phone and internet plans.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[13 Best MagSafe Power Banks for iPhones (2026), Tested and Reviewed]]></title><link>https://www.wired.com/gallery/best-magsafe-power-banks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 12:30:00 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[Keep your iPhone or Qi2 Android phone topped up with one of these WIRED-tested Qi2 or MagSafe portable chargers.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[One of the best budget Android tablets I've tested replaced both my iPad and Kindle]]></title><link>https://www.zdnet.com/article/oneplus-pad-go-2-tablet-review/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 12:30:00 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[The OnePlus Pad Go 2 is a worthy alternative that's priced affordably for what it offers.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[Slow Wi-Fi? I found 10 proven ways to fix your internet this weekend (most are free)]]></title><link>https://www.zdnet.com/article/bad-wifi-10-fixes-for-better-internet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 12:28:00 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[I spent a weekend tweaking my home network to improve my Wi-Fi speed and connectivity. Here's what worked.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[I wrote Linux bash scripts on Android without breaking anything - here's how you can, too]]></title><link>https://www.zdnet.com/article/linux-bash-scripts-how-to-learn-on-android-device/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 12:26:00 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[Enable the Linux terminal on any Android device, and you can create or practice your bash scripting on the go.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[7 ChatGPT settings tweaks that I can no longer work without - and I'm a power user]]></title><link>https://www.zdnet.com/article/chatgpt-settings-for-pro-users/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 12:24:00 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[Stop using ChatGPT on factory settings. Here are the top adjustments I use to make it a pro tool.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[Anthropic Invests $20 Million in Super PAC to Counter OpenAI]]></title><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2026/02/12/technology/anthropic-super-pac-openai.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 12:07:05 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[Anthropic and OpenAI now have their own well-funded political groups that will square off in the midterm elections over artificial intelligence safety and regulation.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[Microsoft's February Patch fixes 6 zero-days - but some Windows users shouldn't update yet]]></title><link>https://www.zdnet.com/article/microsofts-february-patch-tuesday-update/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 12:03:00 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[I'm normally in favor of updating ASAP, but recent events have given me pause.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[The best VPN extensions for Chrome in 2026: Expert tested and reviewed]]></title><link>https://www.zdnet.com/article/best-chrome-vpn/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 12:00:48 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[These are the best VPN extensions for Chrome that will protect your privacy without disrupting your browsing experience.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[We let Chrome's Auto Browse agent surf the web for us—here's what happened]]></title><link>https://arstechnica.com/google/2026/02/tested-how-chromes-auto-browse-agent-handles-common-web-tasks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 12:00:14 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[Auto Browse is capable of some impressive things, but it can also crash and burn spectacularly.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[HP ZBook Ultra G1a review: a business-class workstation that’s got game]]></title><link>https://www.theverge.com/tech/877688/hp-zbook-ultra-g1a-laptop-amd-strix-halo-review</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[Sleeper laptop. | Photo: Antonio G. Di Benedetto / The Verge	

Business laptops are typically dull computers foisted on employees en masse. But higher-end enterprise workstation notebooks sometimes get an interesting enough blend of power and features to appeal to enthusiasts. HP's ZBook Ultra G1a is a nice example. It's easy to see it as another gray boring-book for spendy business types, until you notice a few key specs: an AMD Strix Halo APU, lots of RAM, an OLED display, and an adequate amount of speedy ports (Thunderbolt 4, even - a rarity on AMD laptops).
I know from my time with the Asus ROG Flow Z13 and Framework Desktop that anything using AMD's high-end Ryzen AI Max chips should make for a co …
Read the full story at The Verge.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[Therabody JetBoots Pro Plus Review: 3-in-1 Recovery Tech]]></title><link>https://www.wired.com/review/review-therabody-jetboots-pro-plus/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[The JetBoots Pro Plus promise faster, more effective recovery by combining multiple therapies in one device. I tested whether it’s worth the $1,150 splurge.]]></description></item>
<item><title><![CDATA[Finally, I found a MagSafe power bank that's fit for traveling (and fancy dinners)]]></title><link>https://www.zdnet.com/article/twelve-south-power-capsule-charger-review/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 11:56:00 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[Twelve South's thin and light Power Capsule is textured in cactus leather and available in 5k or 10k mAh capacities.]]></description></item></channel></rss>